Guide to the William Wordsworth collection, 1656-1987
Wordsworth, William collection, 1656-1987
- Dove Cottage manuscripts, photocopies
  - William Wordsworth, Various sonnets and poems, Scotch tour and Italian tour, D.C. Ms. Verse 92, photocopy, 1837-1846; 154
  - William Wordsworth, Fragment of a letter from W.W. to D.W. containing Sonnet on ballot and part of the sonnet beginning "O what a wreck", D.C. Ms. Verse 93, photocopy, Feb.-Mar. 1838; 155
  - William Wordsworth, On the ground of Waterloo..., D.C. Ms. Verse 94, photocopy, Circa 1838; 156
  - William Wordsworth, The cuckoo clock, D.C. Ms. Verse 95, photocopy, 1840; 157
  - William Wordsworth, The cuckoo clock, D.C. Ms. Verse 96, photocopy, 1840; 158
  - William Wordsworth, Private memorials not to be printed, D.C. Ms. Verse 97, photocopy, Circa 1840; 159
  - William Wordsworth, A Jewish family, D.C. Ms. Verse 98, photocopy, 1842; 160
  - William Wordsworth, The Westmorland Girl, transcribed by Mary Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Verse 99, photocopy, 1845; 161 tiny
  - William Wordsworth, Translation of Virgil's Aeneid, D.C. Ms. Verse 100A, photocopy, Circa 1842; 162
  - William Wordsworth, Translation of Virgil's Aeneid, D.C. Ms. Verse 100B, photocopy, Circa 1842; 163
  - William Wordsworth, Large folio of poems, D.C. Ms. Verse 101, photocopy, Circa 1820-1846; 164
  - William Wordsworth, Memorials of a tour in Italy, mss. and revisions for 1842 edition, D.C. Ms. Verse 102, part 1, photocopy, Circa 1842; 165
  - William Wordsworth, Incidents on Salisbury Plain, The Schoolmaster, Address to the scholars of the village school..., At the grave of Burns, D.C. Ms. Verse 102, part 2, photocopy, Circa 1789-1821; 166
  - William Wordsworth, Memorials of a tour in Italy, mss. of the notes to the 1842 edition, D.C. Ms. Verse 102, part 3, photocopy, Circa 1842; 167
  - William Wordsworth, Memorials of a tour in Italy, drafts as returned from the printer, D.C. Ms. Verse 102, part 4, photocopy, Circa 1842; 168
  - William Wordsworth, Memorials of a tour in Italy, drafts as returned from the printer, D.C. Ms. Verse 102, part 5, photocopy, Circa 1842; 169
  - William Wordsworth, Memorials of a tour in Italy, revised proofs of 1842 edition, D.C. Ms. Verse 102, part 6, photocopy, Circa 1842; 170
  - William Wordsworth, A letter to the Bishop of Llandaff on the extraordinary avowal of his political principles contained in the appendix to his late sermon, D.C. Ms. Prose 1, photocopy, 1793; 171
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to John Wilson, D.C. Ms. Prose 2, photocopy, Jun. 1802; 172
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to a friend on the education of a daughter, D.C. Ms. Prose 3, photocopy, 1806; 173
  - William Wordsworth, Draft of letter to Lady Beaumont, D.C. Ms. Prose 4, photocopy, May 21, 1807; 174
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to Wrangham on education, D.C. Ms. Prose 5, photocopy, Jun. 5, 1808; 175
  - William Wordsworth, Essays upon epitaphs, D.C. Ms. Prose 6, photocopy, 1809; 176
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to William Godwin and Charles Pasley, D.C. Ms. Prose 7 and 8, photocopy, 1811; 177
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to William Godwin and Charles Pasley, D.C. Ms. Prose 7 and 8, photocopy, 1811; 178
  - William Wordsworth, Draft of two letters to Lord Lonsdale, D.C. Ms. Prose 9, photocopy, Dec. 27, 1812, Jan. 8, 1813; 179
  - William Wordsworth, Draft of two letters to Lord Lonsdale, D.C. Ms. Prose 9, photocopy, Dec. 27, 1812, Jan. 8, 1813; 180
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to a friend on the Burns memorial, D.C. Ms. Prose 10, photocopy, April 21, 1819; 181
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to a friend on the Burns memorial, D.C. Ms. Prose 10, photocopy, April 21, 1819; 182
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to James Losh, D.C. Ms. Prose 11, photocopy, Dec. 4, 1821; 183
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to James Losh, D.C. Ms. Prose 11, photocopy, Dec. 4, 1821; 184
  - William Wordsworth, Drafts of letter to Charles James Blomfield, Bishop of London, D.C. Ms. Prose 12, photocopy, 1829; 185
  - William Wordsworth, Drafts of letter to Charles James Blomfield, Bishop of London, D.C. Ms. Prose 12, photocopy, 1829; 186
  - William Wordsworth, Draft of two letters to Lord Lonsdale on the Reform Bill, D.C. Ms. Prose 13, photocopy, 1832; 187
  - William Wordsworth, Draft for Appendix to the 1835 edition of the Poems, D.C. Ms. Prose 14, photocopy, Circa 1835; 188
  - William Wordsworth, Letters on the Kendal and Windermere Railway, D.C. Ms. Prose 15, photocopy, 1844; 189
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to Seymour Femenhere, Esq., on education, D.C. Ms. Prose 16, photocopy, Dec. 16, 1845; 190 tiny
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to a friend (T. Clarkson?) on sitting for University Honours, D.C. Ms. Prose 17, photocopy, 1816; 191
  - William Wordsworth, Unidentified manuscript, D.C. Ms. Prose 18, photocopy, Circa 1800-1820; 192
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Approaches-Lancaster-Furness Abbey, General Introduction, D.C. Ms. Prose 19, photocopy, Circa 1810; 193
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Dunnerdale, D.C. Ms. Prose 20, photocopy, Circa 1810; 194
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Coniston Lake, D.C. Ms. Prose 21, photocopy, Circa 1810; 195
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Tilberthwaite and Yewdale, D.C. Ms. Prose 22, photocopy, Circa 1810; 196
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Coniston-Hawkshead-To the Feny, D.C. Ms. Prose 23, photocopy, Circa 1810; 197
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Windermere, Bowness, Staveley, D.C. Ms. Prose 24, photocopy, Circa 1810; 198
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Grasmere and Thirlmere, D.C. Ms. Prose 25, photocopy, Circa 1810; 199
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Borrowdale, D.C. Ms. Prose 26, photocopy, Circa 1810; 200
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Patterdale, Ullswater, etc., D.C. Ms. Prose 27, photocopy, Circa 1810; 201
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: The Sublime and the Beautiful, D.C. Ms. Prose 28, photocopy, Circa 1810; 202
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Keswick to Buttermere, D.C. Ms. Prose 29, photocopy, Circa 1810; 203
  - William Wordsworth, Guide to the lakes: Lakes and islands, D.C. Ms. Prose 30, photocopy, Circa 1810; 204
  - William Wordsworth, Notebook kept at Grasmere, D.C. Ms. Prose 31, photocopy, 1800-1802; 205
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 1 and 2, photocopy, 1798, 1802; 206
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Grasmere Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 3, photocopy, May 14-Dec. 22, 1800; 207 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Grasmere Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 4, photocopy, Oct. 10, 1801-Feb. 14, 1802; 208 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Grasmere journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 5, photocopy, Feb. 14-May 12, 1802; 209 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Grasmere journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 6, photocopy, May 4, 1802-Jan. 16, 1803; 210 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Pencil memoranda of Scotch tour, D.C. Ms. Journal 7, photocopy, Circa 1803; 211 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Recollections of a tour in Scotland, 1803, copied by Mrs. Clarkson (Ms. A), D.C. Ms. Journal 8, photocopy, Circa 1804-1805; 212
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Recollections of a tour in Scotland, 1803 (Ms. B), D.C. Ms. Journal 9, photocopy, 1804-1805; 213
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Recollections of a tour in Scotland, 1803 (Ms. B), D.C. Ms. Journal 10, photocopy, Circa 1805; 214
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Recollections of a tour in Scotland, 1803 (Ms. B), D.C. Ms. Journal 11, photocopy, Circa 1805; 215
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Recollections of a tour in Scotland, 1822-1823 revision, D.C. Ms. Journal 12A, photocopy, 1822-1823; 216
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Recollections of a tour in Scotland, 1822-1823 revision, D.C. Ms. Journal 12B, photocopy, 1822-1823; 217
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Excursion to Ullswater, D.C. Ms. Journal 13, photocopy, Nov. 1805; 218
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, A narrative concerning George and Sarah Green, D.C. Ms. Journal 14, photocopy, May 1808; 219
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Diary of William, Mary, and Dorothy's tour of the Continent, D.C. Ms. Journal 15, part 1, photocopy, 1820; 220
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Diary of William, Mary, and Dorothy's tour of the Continent, D.C. Ms. Journal 15, part 2, photocopy, 1820; 221
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Rough notes for journal of Scotch tour, D.C. Ms. Journal 16, photocopy, 1822; 222
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal of second tour in Scotland, D.C. Ms. Journal 17, photocopy, 1822; 223
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 1, photocopy, Dec. 1, 1824-Dec. 9, 1825; 224 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 2, photocopy, Feb. 10-Jun. 22, 1826; 225
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 3, photocopy, Jun. 29-Sept. 24, 1826; 226
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 4, photocopy, Sept. 25-Nov.1, 1826; 227
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 5, photocopy, Nov.1, 1826-Apr. 13, 1827; 228 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 6, photocopy, April 24-Nov.10, 1827; 229
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 7, photocopy, Nov.11, 1827-Jun. 24, 1828; 230
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 8, photocopy, Jun. 26-Jul. 10, 1828; 231 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 9, photocopy, Jul. 10-Nov. 19, 1828; 232 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 18, part 10, photocopy, Nov. 17, 1828-Dec 1829; 233 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 19, part 1, photocopy, Jan. 21-Aug. 9, 1830; 234
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 19, part 2, photocopy, Aug. 9, 1830-Feb. 12, 1831; 235
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 19, part 3, photocopy, Feb. 12, 1831-Sept. 8, 1833; 236
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 19, part 4, photocopy, Feb. 6-Oct. 3, 1834; 237 tiny
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Journal, D.C. Ms. Journal 19, part 5, photocopy, Oct. 4, 1834-Nov. 4, 1835; 238
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Notes on readings, D.C. Ms. Journal 20, photocopy, Circa 1835; 239
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Copies of poems by William Wordsworth and Dorothy Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Journal 21, photocopy, Circa 1826-1832; 240
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Pet lamb and three poems, D.C. Ms. Journal 22, photocopy, Circa 1826-1832; 241
  - Mary Wordsworth, Notes for Journal of a tour on the Continent, D.C. Ms. Journal 23, part 1, photocopy, 1820; 242 tiny
  - Mary Wordsworth, Notes for Journal of a tour on the Continent, D.C. Ms. Journal 23, part 2, photocopy, 1820; 243
  - Mary Wordsworth, Notes for Journal of a tour on the Continent, D.C. Ms. Journal 23, part 3, photocopy, 1820; 244
  - Mary Wordsworth, Notes for Journal of a tour on the Continent, D.C. Ms. Journal 23, part 4, photocopy, 1820; 245
  - Mary Wordsworth, Journal of a tour on the Continent, 1820, D.C. Ms. Journal 24, photocopy, 1821; 246
  - Mary Wordsworth, Journal of a tour on the Continent, 1820, amended draft, D.C. Ms. Journal 25, photocopy, Circa 1821; 247
  - Mary Wordsworth, Journal of a tour on the Continent, 1820, copied by Sara Hutchinson, D.C. Ms. Journal 26, photocopy, Circa 1821; 248
  - Mary Wordsworth, Journal of a tour on the Continent, 1820, unidentified copyist, D.C. Ms. Journal 27, photocopy, Circa 1821; 249
  - William Wordsworth, Transcripts of scraps written to William Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Journal 28, photocopy, Nov. 1851; 250
  - Mary Wordsworth, Tour in Holland, D.C. Ms. Journal 29, photocopy, 1823; 251
  - Dora Wordsworth, Journal of a tour on the Continent, D.C. Ms. Journal 30, photocopy, 1828; 252 tiny
  - Sara Hutchinson, Journal of a Scotch tour, partly transcribed by Mary Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Journal 31, photocopy, 1814; 253
  - Basil Montagu, Narrative, D.C. Ms. Journal 32, photocopy, Circa 1811-1813; 254
  - Accounts between Richard Wordsworth and William and Dorothy Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 1, photocopy, 1790-1816; 255
  - The Lowther debt to the family of the late John Wordsworth, Esq., D.C. Ms. Misc. 2, photocopy, 1802-1804; 256
  - Accounts and miscellaneous papers conneted with the legacy of Raisley Calvert, Esq., to William Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 3, photocopy, 1794-1798; 257
  - Papers connected with the accounts between Basil Montagu, Esq., and William Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 4, photocopy, 1793-1806; 258
  - Accounts with W. Crackanthorpe, as between the children of John Wordswoth, of Cockermouth, and W. Crackanthorpe's father and grandfather, D.C. Ms. Misc. 5, photocopy, 1813; 259
  - John Wordsworth, Rental of lands and schedule of real and personal securities belonging to John Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 6a, photocopy, 1760-1773; 260
  - Dora Wordsworth, Collection of letters (autograph book), D.C. Ms. Misc. 7, photocopy, Circa 1804-1847; 261
  - Extracts from and summary of accounts current between Richard Wordsworth and the administrators of John Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 8, photocopy, 1794; 262
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to Sir George Beaumont, D.C. Ms. Misc. 9, photocopy, Oct. 14, 1803-Feb. 11, 1806, Sept. 20, 1824; 263
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Letters to Lady Beaumont, D.C. Ms. Misc. 10, photocopy, Apr. 17, 1804-Apr. 20, 1806; 264
  - William Wordsworth, Letter to Lady Beaumont, D.C. Ms. Misc. 11, photocopy, Nov. 20, 1811; 265
  - Catalogue of the mss., etc., in the Wordsworth Museum at Grasmere, D.C. Ms. Misc. 12, photocopy, Circa 1950-1960; 266
  - William Wordsworth, Names of strangers who have visited Rydal Mount since May 8th, 1830, D.C. Ms. Misc. 12a, photocopy, 1830-1848; 267
  - Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Letters, mainly to William Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 13, photocopy, 1799-1823; 268
  - Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Letters to Sara Hutchinson, D.C. Ms. Misc. 14, photocopy, 1802-1804; 269
  - William and Dorothy Wordsworth, Letters to Samuel Taylor Coleridge, D.C. Ms. Misc. 15, photocopy, Circa 1798-1809; 270
  - C. Clarkson and Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Letters to William Wordsworth and Charles Lamb concerning the misunderstanding between Wordsworth and Coleridge, D.C. Ms. Misc. 16, photocopy, May 1812; 271
  - Christopher Wordsworth, Letters to William Wordsworth relating to the last illness and death of Richard Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 17, photocopy, May 1816; 272
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to Christopher Wordsworth on the affairs and death of Richard Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 18, photocopy, Jan.-May 1816; 273
  - Christopher Wordsworth, Letters to William Wordsworth on the administration of the Stockbridge Estate, etc., after the death of Richard Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 19, photocopy, 1816-1818; 274
  - William and Christopher Wordsworth, Letters to John Wordsworth of Stockbridge, D.C. Ms. Misc. 20, photocopy, 1833-1836; 275
  - Thomas de Quincey, Early letters to William and Dorothy Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 21, photocopy, 1803-1808; 276
  - Thomas de Quincey, Letters to William and Dorothy Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 22, photocopy, Mar.-Apr. 1809; 277
  - Thomas de Quincey, Letters to William, Dorothy, and Mary Wordsworth and Sara Hutchinson, D.C. Ms. Misc. 23, photocopy, May-Sept. 1809; 278
  - Thomas de Quincey, Letters to William, Dorothy, and Mary Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 24, photocopy, 1810, 1812-1813; 279
  - Thomas de Quincey, Letters to William and Dorothy Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 25, photocopy, 1818-1825; 280
  - William Wordsworth, Desciptive Sketches, Wordsworth's copy with notes, D.C. Ms. Misc. 26, photocopy, 1793; 281
  - William Wordsworth, Fenwick notes, D.C. Ms. Misc. 27, photocopy, 1843; 282
  - Charles Lamb, The king and queen of hearts, Directions for visiting him at Enfield, D.C. Ms. Misc. 28, photocopy, 1805, 1828 or 1829; 283 tiny
  - Charles Lamb, The king and queen of hearts: an 1805 book for children, D.C. Ms. Misc. 29, photocopy, 1902; 284 tiny
  - Charles Lamb and Dorothy Wordsworth, Papers related to Charles Lamb's purchase of books for Dorothy Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 30, photocopy, Jan. 1806; 285
  - Charles and Mary Lamb, Seven poems published in the works of Charles Lamb, 1818, D.C. Ms. Misc. 31, photocopy, Circa 1805 and earlier; 286
  - Charles Lamb, Miscellaneous letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 32, photocopy, Circa 1823; 287
  - Charles Lamb, Fragment of notes written to Moxon, D.C. Ms. Misc. 33, photocopy, Circa 1820s; 288
  - Mary Wordsworth, Miscellaneous letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 34, photocopy, 1824-1857; 289
  - Mary and Dorothy Wordsworth, Letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 35, photocopy, 1790-1799; 290
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to Dora and Mary Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 36, photocopy, 1827-1830; 291
  - Mary and Dorothy Wordsworth, Letters to Mrs. Clarkson, D.C. Ms. Misc. 37, photocopy, 1805, 1837, 1845; 292
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to Mary and Dorothy Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 38, photocopy, Aug.-Sept. 1829; 293
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to his family, D.C. Ms. Misc. 39, photocopy, 1829-1834; 294
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 40, photocopy, 1829-1846; 295
  - William Wordsworth, Letters from the Continent, D.C. Ms. Misc. 41, photocopy, Mar.-Jul. 1837; 296
  - William and Mary Wordsworth, Letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 42, photocopy, Jul.-Sept. 1837; 297
  - Sara Hutchinson, Letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 43, photocopy, Circa 1816-1818; 298
  - Mary Wordsworth, Letters on the Catholic Relief Bill, D.C. Ms. Misc. 44, photocopy, 1825; 299
  - William and Mary Wordsworth, Letters, chiefly to Dora Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 45, photocopy, Apr.-Jun. 1839; 300
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to Dorothy Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 46, photocopy, 1838-1842; 301
  - William Wordsworth, Miscellaneous letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 47, photocopy, 1829-1845; 302
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Letters to John Marshall, D.C. Ms. Misc. 48, photocopy, 1827-1828; 303
  - Dorothy Wordsworth, Letters to William Wordsworth written from the Clarkson's house, D.C. Ms. Misc. 49, photocopy, Aug. 1810; 304
  - John Wordsworth, Letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 50, photocopy, 1792-1801; 305
  - John Wordsworth, Letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 51, photocopy, 1792-1805; 306
  - John Wordsworth, Letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 52, photocopy, Mar. 1801-Jan. 1805; 307
  - John Wordsworth, Letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 53, photocopy, 1804-1805; 308
  - William, Dorothy, and Richard Wordsworth, Correspondence concerning the death of John Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 54, photocopy, Feb.-Apr. 1805; 309
  - Misc. correspondence concerning the death of John Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 55, photocopy, 1805; 310
  - Misc. papers and letters concerning John Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 56, photocopy, Circa 1892-1932; 311
  - William, Dorothy, and Mary Wordsworth, Letters to Miss Fenwick, D.C. Ms. Misc. 57, part 1, photocopy, 1835-1840; 312
  - William, Dorothy, and Mary Wordsworth, Letters to Miss Fenwick, D.C. Ms. Misc. 57, part 2, photocopy, 1841-1843; 313
  - William, Dorothy, and Mary Wordsworth and Edward Quillinan, Letters to Miss Fenwick, D.C. Ms. Misc. 57, part 3, photocopy, 1844-1846; 314
  - William, Dorothy, and Mary Wordsworth and Edward Quillinan, Letters to Miss Fenwick, D.C. Ms. Misc. 57, part 4, photocopy, 1847-1849; 315
  - Mary Wordsworth and Edward Quillinan, Letters to Miss Fenwick, D.C. Ms. Misc. 57, part 5, photocopy, 1850-1854; 316
  - William Wordsworth, Letters to Miss Fenwick, D.C. Ms. Misc. 58, photocopy, Circa 1835-1850; 317
  - S. Rogers, Robert Southey, and others, Letters to William Wordsworth on the death of Sara Hutchinson and Dora Quillinan, D.C. Ms. Misc. 59, photocopy, Circa 1835-1850; 318
  - Wordsworth family, Miscellaneous letters, D.C. Ms. Misc. 60, photocopy, 1813-1859; 319
  - William and Dorothy Wordsworth, Letters to Christopher Wordsworth and family, D.C. Ms. Misc. 61, photocopy, 1814-1847; 320
  - Letters to Richard Wordsworth from various members of his family, D.C. Ms. Misc. 62, photocopy, 1794-1804; 321
  - Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Dejection: an ode, D.C. Ms. Misc. 63, photocopy, April 4, 1802; 322
  - William Wordsworth, Proof of Ode in memory of Charles Lamb, with alterations in the hand of Mary Wordsworth, D.C. Ms. Misc. 64, photocopy, Circa 1834; 323
  - Robert Southey, Miscellaneous manuscripts, D.C. Ms. Misc. 65, photocopy, Circa 1800-1843; 324 tiny
  - William Wordsworth, Epitaph on Robert Southey, D.C. Ms. Misc. 66, photocopy, Circa 1843; 325
  - William and Dorothy Wordsworth and Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Correspondence, D.C. Ms. Misc. 67, photocopy, 1804-1807; 326
  - Misc. newspaper clippings, D.C. Ms. Misc. 68, photocopy, Circa 1800; 327
  - Narrative I of the Loss of the Earl of Abergavenny, Captain John Wordsworth's ship, D.C. Ms. Misc. 69, part 1, photocopy, 1805; 328
  - Narrative II of the Loss of the Earl of Abergavenny, Captain John Wordsworth's ship, D.C. Ms. Misc. 69, part 2, photocopy, 1805; 329
  - Narrative III of the Loss of the Earl of Abergavenny, Captain John Wordsworth's ship, D.C. Ms. Misc. 69, part 3, photocopy, 1805; 330
  - John Wordsworth, Miscellaneous accounts, documents, etc., D.C. Ms. Misc. 6, photocopy, Circa 1773-1793; 331